They've saved the best trip for last... But this
time they may have gone too far.
Back to the Future Part III is a adventure, comedy, science
fiction film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
The final installment finds Marty digging the trusty DeLorean out of a
mineshaft and looking for Doc in the Wild West of 1885.
But when their time machine breaks down, the
travelers are stranded in a land of spurs.
More problems arise when Doc falls for pretty schoolteacher Clara
Clayton, and Marty tangles with Buford Tannen.
Marty McFly / Seamus McFly, played by Michael J. Fox.
Doctor Emmett Brown, played by Christopher Lloyd.
Clara Clayton, played by Mary Steenburgen.
Buford 'Mad Dog' Tannen / Biff Tannen, played by Thomas F. Wilson.
Maggie McFly / Lorraine McFly, played by Lea Thompson.
Jennifer, played by Elisabeth Shue.
Back to the Future Part III is a 1990 American science fiction Western film
and the third installment of the Back to the Future trilogy.
The film was directed by Robert Zemeckis, and stars Michael J.
Fox, Christopher Lloyd, Mary Steenburgen, Thomas F.
Wilson, and Lea Thompson.
The film continues immediately after Back to the Future Part II (1989); while stranded in 1955
during his time travel adventures, Marty McFly (Fox) discovers that his friend Dr.
Emmett "Doc" Brown (Lloyd) is trapped in 1885 and was killed by Biff's
great-grandfather Buford "Mad Dog" Tannen (Wilson).
Marty travels to 1885 with the intent of rescuing Doc and then return to 1985, but matters
are complicated when Doc falls in love with Clara Clayton (Steenburgen).
Back to the Future Part III was filmed in California and Arizona, and was
produced on a $40 million budget back-to-back with Part II.
Part III was released in the United States on May 25, 1990, six months after the previous installment, and grossed
$245 million worldwide during its initial run, making it the sixth-highest-grossing film of 1990.
The film received a positive response from critics, who
noted it as an improvement over Part II.
The film explores themes of california, saloon,
sports car, inventor, horseback riding.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking and intense.